<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Vithurshan SELVARAJAH</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Vithurshan SELVARAJAH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.atomicl.net/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Encrypt external drives with Linux Unified Key Setup (LUKS)</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/luks_encrypt_external_drives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/luks_encrypt_external_drives/</guid><description>1. Find your drive In order to find the correct drive to encrypt, run the lsblk command, then plug in your external storage device and run the lsblk command again. And now by comparing you can identify a new one appeared in the output of the last executed command.
The /dev/sdX drive referenced in this article is an imaginary device and be sure to replace it with your real device.</description></item><item><title>Pentester's Toolbox</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/toolbox/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/toolbox/</guid><description>Table of Content&amp;#xa0;&amp;#xa0;&amp;#xa0;toc 1. Web Enumeration
1.1. Feroxbuster 1.2. Wfuzz 1.3. Whatweb 1.4. WPScan 2. Network Pivot
2.1. Ligolo-ng 3. Bind Shell | Reverse Shell | File Transfer
3.1. Powercat 3.2. Socat 3.3. Powershell 4. Remote Shell on Windows
4.1. Impacket-wmiexec 4.2. Impacket-psexec 4.3. Evil-winrm 4.4. Enter-PSSession 4.5. Pywinrm 5. Passwords Extraction
5.1. Mimikatz 5.2. Impacket-secretsdump 6. Linux Privilege Escalation
6.1. LinEnum - Linux PrivEsc 6.2. LinPEAS - Linux PrivEsc 6.</description></item><item><title>Change Users Default Shell</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/change_users_default_shell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/change_users_default_shell/</guid><description>The shell is a program that interprets commands that we enter and there are several shells such as bash, sh, ksh, zsh, fish and many more. Bash (/bin/bash) is a popular shell on most if not all Linux systems, and it’s normally the default shell for user accounts.
We can also change or define a shell for a user to provide more functionality or block access to the shell using /sbin/nologin.</description></item><item><title>Install FTP Server</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/install_ftp_server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/install_ftp_server/</guid><description>Introduction FTP stands for File Transfer Protocol which is used for transferring file between a centralized server and clients over a network. This tutorial describes the installation, configuration and securing process of FTP server. This tutorial uses VSFTPD as a FTP server software which stands Very Secure FTP Daemon.
The communication between FTP client and server is done by using two type of connection namely control connection and a data connection.</description></item></channel></rss>