<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mail on Vithurshan SELVARAJAH</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/tags/mail/</link><description>Recent content in Mail on Vithurshan SELVARAJAH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.atomicl.net/tags/mail/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DomainKeys Identified Mail (DKIM)</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/projects/mail/domainkeys-identified-mail/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/projects/mail/domainkeys-identified-mail/</guid><description>Email sender spoofing involves pretending to control another person&amp;#39;s email address. Scammers often send emails with a sender address like someone@paypal.com and hope that the recipient will fall for it and trust them. In fact, SMTP doesn&amp;#39;t care what sender address you send from. Many email service providers require you to send emails only with your own email address. But some don&amp;#39;t.
To avoid this problem, a new method was conceived that add a cryptographic signature to the header of an email, which the recipient can check to verify the authenticity of the sender and the integrity of the email.</description></item><item><title>Emacs as Email Client</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/emacs-mu4e/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/emacs-mu4e/</guid><description>Emacs Mu4e We can use Emacs to consult mails with the help of various programs. Among them, Mu4e is a mail client for Emacs and it is considered as an Emacs interface for mu the mail indexer. A typical example might be a mail sync program like isync which downloads mail from the remote Maildir folder to the local Maildir folder and then the mu indexer will be used to index the mail.</description></item><item><title>Offline Email with Isync</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/isync/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/isync/</guid><description>Isync Install isync using your package manager, here we are installing the apt package manager, but use whatever package manager you are using:
sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt install isync We will use isync program to download mails to local Maildir folder. We can also use a program called offlineimap which is a bit slower but it can work on Windows. NOTE: isync is the name of the project, mbsync is the name of the executable.</description></item></channel></rss>