<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English on Vithurshan SELVARAJAH</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/languages/english/</link><description>Recent content in English on Vithurshan SELVARAJAH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.atomicl.net/languages/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>"Brain Not Good at Qualifying Information"</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/posts/brain_not_good_at_qualifying_information/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/posts/brain_not_good_at_qualifying_information/</guid><description>🧠💡 Unlocking the Secrets of the Brain! 🚀
Ever wondered why our brains sometimes prioritize recently learned info over what&amp;#39;s truly important? 🤔 It&amp;#39;s like having a mental &amp;#34;Last In, First Out&amp;#34; (LIFO) system! 🔄
The brain tends to overestimate the importance of facts that are easily retrieved, creating a &amp;#34;Feature-positive&amp;#34; effect. 🌟 This means we might neglect valuable, harder-to-recall information in favor of the latest tidbits.
⚖️ But fear not!</description></item><item><title>Hermeneutic circle</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/posts/hermeneutic_circle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/posts/hermeneutic_circle/</guid><description>📌 Have you ever heard of the Hermeneutic circle of Hans-Georg Gadamer ?
💡 That is exactly what applies to cybersecurity. We can&amp;rsquo;t just explain a topic in cybersecurity without addressing related topics like networks, programming, systems, and other vulnerabilities.
What I learned after some of these years of study is that learning pentesting/cybersecurity is not a linear process, you can&amp;rsquo;t start from scratch.
References https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermeneutic_circle https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hans-Georg_Gadamer</description></item><item><title>Emacs as Email Client</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/emacs-mu4e/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/emacs-mu4e/</guid><description>Emacs Mu4e We can use Emacs to consult mails with the help of various programs. Among them, Mu4e is a mail client for Emacs and it is considered as an Emacs interface for mu the mail indexer. A typical example might be a mail sync program like isync which downloads mail from the remote Maildir folder to the local Maildir folder and then the mu indexer will be used to index the mail.</description></item><item><title>Offline Email with Isync</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/isync/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/isync/</guid><description>Isync Install isync using your package manager, here we are installing the apt package manager, but use whatever package manager you are using:
sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt install isync We will use isync program to download mails to local Maildir folder. We can also use a program called offlineimap which is a bit slower but it can work on Windows. NOTE: isync is the name of the project, mbsync is the name of the executable.</description></item><item><title>Pentester's Toolbox</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/toolbox/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/toolbox/</guid><description>Table of Content&amp;#xa0;&amp;#xa0;&amp;#xa0;toc 1. Web Enumeration
1.1. Feroxbuster 1.2. Wfuzz 1.3. Whatweb 1.4. WPScan 2. Network Pivot
2.1. Ligolo-ng 3. Bind Shell | Reverse Shell | File Transfer
3.1. Powercat 3.2. Socat 3.3. Powershell 4. Remote Shell on Windows
4.1. Impacket-wmiexec 4.2. Impacket-psexec 4.3. Evil-winrm 4.4. Enter-PSSession 4.5. Pywinrm 5. Passwords Extraction
5.1. Mimikatz 5.2. Impacket-secretsdump 6. Linux Privilege Escalation
6.1. LinEnum - Linux PrivEsc 6.2. LinPEAS - Linux PrivEsc 6.</description></item><item><title>Change Users Default Shell</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/change_users_default_shell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/change_users_default_shell/</guid><description>The shell is a program that interprets commands that we enter and there are several shells such as bash, sh, ksh, zsh, fish and many more. Bash (/bin/bash) is a popular shell on most if not all Linux systems, and it’s normally the default shell for user accounts.
We can also change or define a shell for a user to provide more functionality or block access to the shell using /sbin/nologin.</description></item><item><title>Install FTP Server</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/install_ftp_server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/install_ftp_server/</guid><description>Introduction FTP stands for File Transfer Protocol which is used for transferring file between a centralized server and clients over a network. This tutorial describes the installation, configuration and securing process of FTP server. This tutorial uses VSFTPD as a FTP server software which stands Very Secure FTP Daemon.
The communication between FTP client and server is done by using two type of connection namely control connection and a data connection.</description></item><item><title>Programs I Use</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/ecosystem/software/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/ecosystem/software/</guid><description>Summary I&amp;rsquo;m a privacy conscious person and use free, minimalist, terminal-based programs on my computer that are easy to maintain in long term. I think a good software should answer your needs rather than the author&amp;rsquo;s. You can find my custom configuration within my .dotfiles folder.
Basic Operating System/Distribution
I like to start with a minimal operating system and then add software as needed. This way I am able to master most of the software on my system and learn things.</description></item><item><title>DWM - Dynamic Window Manager</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/projects/blackdwm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/projects/blackdwm/</guid><description>This is a fork of DWM by suckless.org, an extremely fast, small and dynamic window manager for X. I added many patches and custom configuration to fit into my workflow. Requirements For Debian/Debian based systems sudo apt install make gcc libx11-dev libxft-dev libxinerama-dev xorg For Arch sudo pacman -S base-devel git libx11 libxft xorg-server xorg-xinit terminus-font Installation Clone the git repository:
git clone https://github.com/BlackcatRs/blackdwm.git Edit config.mk to match your local setup (dwm is installed into the /usr/local namespace by default).</description></item><item><title>Forward Local GPG Agent Socket through SSH Tunnel</title><link>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/forward_local_gpg_agent_socket_through_ssh_tunnel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.atomicl.net/notes/forward_local_gpg_agent_socket_through_ssh_tunnel/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Configure SSH Server Forward Local GPG Agent Socket GPG Agent Command Debug Socket Forwarding References Introduction gpg-agent is a daemon used to manage GPG secret (private) keys for the gpg and gpgsm programs. These programs interact with the gpg-agent daemon through a socket to request the secret key and request for the secret key.
If the gpg-agent process has the key, it provides it to gpg. If not, it tries to load the encrypted key from your keyring and prompts you for the key&amp;rsquo;s passphrase.</description></item></channel></rss>